Guide to the Rice University Assistant to the President papers: Carl MacDowell, 1963-2001 (bulk 1990-1998) UA 084
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Assistant to the President papers: Carl MacDowell
1963-2001
bulk
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
MacDowell, Carl
UA 084
103 Linear Feet
The papers in this collection are office records from the Rice University President's Office covering three administrations – Norman Hackerman, George Rupp and Malcolm Gillis. They are a combination of documents to and from Carl MacDowell as Assistant to the President, and in some cases the documents appear to be those directed to the acting president.
Biographical Note
Carl MacDowell began working at Rice University in June 1967 and continued for 32 years. He began as assistant to William Gordon, dean of Science and Engineering. In 1976 he was chosen to become assistant to the president. His tenure in that position lasted through two presidents – Norman Hackerman (1970-85), George Rupp (1985-93) and part of a third, Malcolm Gillis (1993-2004). MacDowell was highly regarded by all who knew and worked with him. Malcolm Gillis said of MacDowell, "Carl gained the trust of generations of students, faculty, and board members, and above all, the presidents he served." His institutional knowledge was essential to managing the school. His love of the school was always apparent. MacDowell earned the trust of everyone who worked with him and knew that he would do the best job he could.
MacDowell retired in January 2000. Mark Scheid replaced him as assistant to the president after working with him in a transitional period.
Scope and Contents
The papers in this collection are office records from the President's Office covering three administrations – Norman Hackerman, George Rupp and Malcolm Gillis. They are a combination of documents to and from Carl MacDowell as Assistant to the President, and in some cases the documents appear to be those directed to the acting president. Many of the later documents appeared to be those directed to Malcolm Gillis. Some of the documents preceding 1976 when MacDowell began as Assistant to the President, appear to be long-term records of agreements, contracts or financial documents retained in the president's office during several administrations.
The majority of the records are paper documents made up of correspondence, news clippings, contracts, speeches, reports, minutes, financial documents, and other types of documents used in conducting the business of the President's Office. There are also a few photographs, a computer disc, cassettes and a March of Dimes plaque.
In Series II On Campus-General, the files are divided into groups by administrative offices, i. e. Admissions, President, VP of Finance and Administration, etc. In some cases the titles of the offices changed over the years. References are noted where possible.
The MIT Faculty Salary surveys were not transferred as part of this collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Access Restrictions
Permission to use the President's Office Records must be obtained in writing from Mark Scheid, Assistant to the President. Legal and disciplinary files need special permission.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the President, Rice University, 2002.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Subjects (Persons)
Hackerman, Norman.; Gillis, Malcolm.; MacDowell, Carl; MacDowell, Carl --Correspondence.; Rupp, George.
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Office of the President; Rice University -- history.
- Series I: Academic Departments, Institutes, and Centers, 1974 - 2000
  Scope and Contents note
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by name of department. Contents of the folders are mostly in original order and the dates that are covered are noted on the folder. One box of legal size (oversize) material is noted.
  Subseries IA – Departmental Annual Reports, 1989 – 1995, 3.75 cubic feet, Boxes 26 – 33. The annual reports in this series were removed from binders (probably from Neal Lane, Provost). They are filed by years and then alphabetically by department. Other annual reports can be found in Series I and in the Series II On Campus-General files under the Dean of the Department's correspondence.
  - Aero-Astronautics Group, 1989-90 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anthropology, 1990-93 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anthropology, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anthropology, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anthropology, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anthropology, 1998-99 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art and Art History, 1988, 1990-92 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art and Art History, 1993-94 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art and Art History, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Art and Art History, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Art and Art History, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - (Institute for the) Arts, 1979, 1982-85, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Asian Studies, 1994-96 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baker Institute for Public Policy (BIPP), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - Archive Agreement, 1985-93 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Campaign Notebook, 1st Edition, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Drafts, 1992-93 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - Invitations/Breakfast Menu, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - BIPP - Notes, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - BIPP - Press Conference, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - BIPP - Press Release/Notification, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - BIPP - Proposal, 1992-93 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BIPP - (The) Americas Project. 1995-98 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - BIPP - Board of Advisors, 1997-99 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - BIPP - Bylaws, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - BIPP - Campaign, 1992, January - June 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - Campaign, July - December 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Campaign, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - Campaign, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Campaign, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - China Project, Coopers and Lybrand/Ford Motor Co., 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - BIPP - Conferences, 1993-94 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - Conferences, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Conferences/(Inaugural) Annual Conference, Nov. 13-14, 1995 (Folder 1) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - Conferences/(Inaugural) Annual Conference, Nov. 13-14 1995 (Folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Conferences/ (Inaugural) Annual Conference (Rice Faculty Papers), Nov. 13-14, 1995 (Folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - Conferences/Annual Conference, Nov. 12-13, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - BIPP - Conferences/Annual Conference and Dedication, Oct. 15- 16, 1997 (Folder 1) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - Conferences/Annual Conference and Dedication, Oct. 15- 16, 1997 (Folder 2) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Conferences/Annual Conference, Nov. 5-6, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - Conferences/Asia Society, Feb. 9-10, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Correspondence and Direction, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - Correspondence and Direction, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - BIPP - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - BIPP - Correspondence, 1996 (Folder 1) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - BIPP - Correspondence, 1996 (Folder 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - Director, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Director Search, 1993-94 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - Director Search, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - BIPP - Groundbreaking, 1994 (Folder 1) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - Groundbreaking, 1994 (Folder 2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Groundbreaking, 1994 (Folder 2) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - Groundbreaking, Oct. 20, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Operating Budget, 1994-95 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - Health Policy Senior Fellow, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - BIPP - (Proposal to) Houston Endowment, Inc. 1993-94 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - BIPP - Institute for Advanced Study, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - BIPP - LaRouche, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - BIPP - Mini University (Johnny Duncan), 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - BIPP - Press, 1993-94 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - BIPP - Press, Djerejian, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - BIPP - Research Projects Advisory Committee, 1997-98 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - BIPP - Roundtable, 1997-98 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - BIPP - Staffing, 1993-95 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - BIPP - Visit/Albright, Madeleine, Feb. 7, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - BIPP - Visit/Annan, Kofi, April 23, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - BIPP - Visit/Arafat, Yasser, March 5, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - BIPP - Visit/Schwarzkopf, General Norman, Sept. 18, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - BIPP - World Energy Congress, Sept. 13-18, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - BIPP - World Trade Organization, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Bio 1997 International, June 1997, Houston, TX (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 1989, 1991-92 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 1996-97 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology/Annual Report, 1993/94 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology/Annual Report, 1994-95 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Biochemistry and Cell Biology/Annual Report, 1995-96 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - (M. D. Anderson) Biological Laboratory, 1994-95 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Biosciences and Bioengineering Institute (BBI), 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - BBI, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - BBI, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - BBI, 1997-99 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Center for Research on Parallel Computation (CRPC), 1992-94 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - CRPC, 1988-95 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - CRPC, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - CRPC/Annual Report, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CRPC, Brochure, and Press Kit, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - CRPC/NSF Renewal Site Visit (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Center for Technology in Teaching and Learning, 1995-96 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Center for the Study of Cultures, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Center for the Study of Cultures, 1995-96 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Center for the Study of Institutions and Values, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Center for the Study of Languages, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1991-92 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1995-96 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1997-98 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry, 1991-92 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Chemistry, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Chemistry, 1995-96 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chemistry, 1997-98 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Chemistry/Building Renovation, 1996-98 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Chemistry/President's Report, 1990-91 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Chemistry/Nobel Laureates, Bob Curl Rick Smalley (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Chemistry/Task Force on Nanotechnology, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Civil Engineering, 1991-92 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Civil Engineering, 1992, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Civil Engineering, 1995-96 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Civil Engineering/Preceptorship Program, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Computer Science, 1997-98 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Computational and Applied Mathematics, 1992-94 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Computational and Applied Mathematics, 1995-96 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Computational and Applied Mathematics, 1997-99 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Computational Engineering, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Computational Engineering, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Computational Engineering, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Computational Engineering/Building Campaign, 1993-94 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Computational Engineering/Dedication, Nov. 1, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Computational Engineering/Groundbreaking, Nov. 4, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Computational Engineering/Notebook 1st Edition, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Computer and Information Technology Institute (CITI), 1988, 1993-97 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Computer Science, 1991-92 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Computer Science, 1994-95 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Computer Science, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Center for Education, 1990-92 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Center for Education, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Center for Education, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Center for Education, June 1994 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Center for Education, 1995-97 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Center for Education/Advisory Board, 1993 (Folder 1) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Center for Education/Advisory Board, 1993 (Folder 2) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Center for Education/Brown Foundation, 1992-94 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Center for Education/Model Science Lab, 1989-91 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Center for Education/Model Science Lab, 1990-92 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Center for Education/Model Science Lab, 1992-96 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Center for Education/HISD Lab School, 1990-92 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Center for Education/HISD Lab School, 1993-94 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Center for Education/HISD Lab School, 1995-96 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Center for Education/HISD Lab School, 1997-98 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Center for Education/Report to the President, 1995-96 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Center for Education/Report to the President Attachment, 1995-96 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Ecology and Evolutional Biology, 1991-92 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Ecology and Evolutional Biology, 1993-94 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Ecology and Evolutional Biology, 1994-96 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Economics, 1988, 1990-92 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Economics, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Economics, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Economics, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Economics, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Economics, 1997-98 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Economics - Sabbaticals and Leaves, 1993, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Education, 1993-94 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Education, 1995-98 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Education/Accreditation Visit, 1982-88 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Education/Summer School for High School Students, 1990-92 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Education/Summer School for High School Students, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1991-92 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1993-94 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Energy and Environmental Science Institute (EESI), 1992-94 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - EESI, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - EESI, 1995-96 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - EESI/DeLange Conference, March 3-5, 1997, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - EESI/DeLange Conference, March 3-5, 1997, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - EESI/DOD Proposal for Applied Technology Demonstration, 1992, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - English, 1986, 1991-92 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - English, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - English, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - English, 1995-96 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - English, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - English/Studies in English Literature, 1991-93, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - English/Writing Program, 1993-94 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - English/Writing Program, 1995-96 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - (Rice) Environmental Conference, Feb. 2-3, 1996, 1995-96 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Environmental Science and Engineering (ESE), 1991-92 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ESE, 1991-92, 1994-99 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - ESE, 1993-94 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - ESE, 1993-94 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ESE, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - ESE, 1995-96 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - ESE, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - ESE/EPA-OER Site Visit, Conflict of Interest/National Center for Ground Water Research, 1991-92 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - ESE/Tuition Waivers, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Feminist Economics, 1993-95 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Feminist Economics, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - French Studies, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - French Studies, 1993-94 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - French Studies, 1995-96 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Geology and Geophysics, 1990-92 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Geology and Geophysics, 1993-94 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Geology and Geophysics, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Geology and Geophysics, 1995-96 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Geology and Geophysics/Research Vessel, 1994-95 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - German and Slavic Studies, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - German and Slavic Studies, 1989, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - German and Slavic Studies, 1992-94 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - German and Slavic Studies, 1995-96 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - History, 1989, 1991-92 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - History, 1993-95 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - History, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - History, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - History, 1997-98 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - History/Journal of Southern History, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - History/Journal of Southern History, 1993-94 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - History/The Papers of Jefferson Davis, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Hispanic and Classical Studies, 1993-94 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Hispanic and Classical Studies, 1995-96 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Hispanic and Classical Studies/Chilean Exchange, 1991-96 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Health Performance and Health Science, 1991-92 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Health Performance and Health Science, 1993-94 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Health Performance and Health Science, 1995-96 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Health Performance and Health Science, 1997-98 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Health Performance and Health Science/Henshaw, 1992, 1995-96 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Latin American Studies, 1993-94 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Linguistics and Semiotics, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Linguistics and Semiotics, 1992-94 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Linguistics, 1995-96 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Managerial Studies, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - (Institute for) Mathematics and Science Foundation, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Mathematics, 1991-92 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Mathematics, 1993-94 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Mathematics, 1995-96 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, 1990-92 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, 1993-94 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, 1995-96 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Medieval Studies 1995, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Nanoscale Science and Technology, 1994-95 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Nanoscale Science and Technology, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Nanoscale Science and Technology, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - (Center for) Nanoscale Science and Technology Leadership Committee, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Nanotechnology, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Nanotechnology, 1993-94 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Nanotechnology, 1993-94 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Nanotechnology, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Nanotechnology, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Nanotechnology, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - National Space Biomedical Research Institute (NSBRI), 1996 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Naval Science, 1991-92 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Naval Science, 1993-94 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Naval Science, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Naval Science, 1996-98 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - NROTC, 1992-94 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - NROTC, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - NROTC, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Philosophy, 1991-92 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy, 1993, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy, 1996-98 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Physics, 1989, 1990-92 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Physics, 1993-94 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Physics, 1994-95 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Physics, 1995-96 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Physics, 1996-97 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Physics/Bonner Lab, 1993-94 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Political Science, 1991-92 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Political Science, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Political Science, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Political Science, 1996-97 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Psychology, 1989-92 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Psychology, 1993-94 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Psychology, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Psychology, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Psychology, 1997-98 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Religious Studies, 1989, 1992-93 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Religious Studies, 1994-96 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Rice Engineering Design and Development Institute (REDDI), 1977 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Rice Institute for Policy Analysis (RIPA), 1993-94 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - RIPA/Harris County Government Handbook Project, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Rice Quantum Institute, 1981-82. 1986-89 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Rice Quantum Institute, 1991-94 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Rice Quantum Institute, 1995-96 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Rice University School Mathematics Program (RUSMP), 1990-92 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - RUSMP, 1993-96 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - ROTC, 1994, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Sewall Art Gallery, 1991-92 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Sewall Art Gallery, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Sewall Art Gallery, 1995-99 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Shepherd School of Music, 1987-88, 1991-93 (Folder 1) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Shepherd School of Music, 1987-88, 1991-93 (Folder 2) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Shepherd School of Music, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Sociology, 1991-92 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Sociology, 1993-94 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Sociology, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Sociology, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Sociology, 1997-98 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy, 1988-92 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy, 1993-94 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy, 1995-96 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy, 1997-98 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Spanish/Portuguese/Classics, 1991-92 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Statistics, 1993-94 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Statistics, 1995-96 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Subseries A: Departmental Annual Reports
    - 1989-93
      - Architecture (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Engineering (Folder 1) (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Engineering (Folder 2) (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Engineering (Folder 3) (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Engineering (Folder 4) (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Humanities (Folder 1) (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Humanities (Folder 2) (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Humanities (Folder 3) (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Humanities (Folder 4) (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Music School, Jones School, Miscellaneous (Folder 1) (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Music School, Jones School, Miscellaneous (Folder 2) (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Natural Sciences (Folder 1) (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Natural Sciences (Folder 2) (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Natural Sciences (Folder 3) (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Sewall Art Gallery (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Social Sciences (Folder 1) (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Social Sciences (Folder 2) (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - 1993-94
      - Social Sciences (Folder 3) (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Incomplete (Folder 1) (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Incomplete (Folder 2) (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Incomplete (Folder 3) (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Responses from Malcolm Gillis and David Auston
      - Anthropology - Computer Science (Folder 1) (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Continuing Studies - Engineering (Folder 2) (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - English - Jones School (Folder 3) (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Linguistics - Statistics (Folder 4) (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - 1994-95
      - Centers and Institutes (Folder 1) (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Centers and Institutes (Folder 2) (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Engineering (Folder 1) (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Engineering (Folder 2) (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Humanities (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 1) (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 2) (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Natural Sciences (Folder 1) (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Natural Sciences (Folder 2) (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Professional Schools (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Social Sciences (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Series II: On Campus - General, 1963 – 2000